Guide to the Professor John Lienhard Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Engines of Our Ingenuity Talks
  - Thinking About Radios, Books, And Machines, 6/5/00 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Luncheon For WSHU Supporters: Whitney, 6/5/00 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Luncheon For WSHU Supporters: BNL, 6/6/00 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Inventing Modern:, 7/23/00 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Notes on Preparing Students To Go Into Engineering, 8/10/00 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Inventing Modern:, 8/25/00 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - On Being Young & Smart, At The Same Time, 8/31/00 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - First Lecture On Greece: Issues on Language, 9/5/00 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - About Astronomy and Learning To See, 9/8/00 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Reflections On Science, Religion, and the Search for Reality, 9/17/00 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - The Age and Other Troublesome Properties of the Earth, 9/19/00 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Reflections Upon Education In The New Millennium, 9/26/00 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - The Soul of the Machine, 10/7/00 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - I Sell Here, Sir, What All The World Desires To Have - Power, 10/18/00 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Inventing Modern:, 10/19/00 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - God The Master Craftsman: Thoughts on Technology and Jubilee, 10/29/00 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Trying To Ride The American Highway Into The Future, 10/30/00 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Introduction For The Stephen Jay Gould Lecture, 11/6/00 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Second Lecture On Greece: We O'ercome By Art, 11/13/00 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Chemistry: An Odyssey of the Mind and of the Eye, 11/16/00 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Innovation: A Dangerous Guest, 11/28/00 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Thinking About Radios, Books, and Machines, 12/12/00 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - God The Master Craftsman: Thoughts On Technology and Jubilee, 12/19/00 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Innovation: A Dangerous Guest, 1/23/01 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Women In Flight: Balloons, Parachutes, Airplanes…, 2/5/01 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - In Which America Invents The Public Library, 2/11/01 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - What Did People Say About Books in 1501, 2/22/01 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Thinking About Scholarship Endowments, 3/1/01 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Jane Marcet, 3/13/01 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Jane Marcet and Her Circle: 19th Century Women and Technology, 3/18/01 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - The Trotula, 3/19/01 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - I Dressed the Wound and God Healed Him, 3/19/01 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Salieri, Mozart, and the Hound of Heaven, 3/25/01 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Finding the Door Into Summer: Dyslexia on a Wintry Day, 3/26/01 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Ever-Present Dangers:, 3/31/01 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - It's Only A Theory, 4/3/01 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - The Wild Card: Creativity and Unpredictability, 4/18/01 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - The Subtle Texture of Cooperation, 4/25/01 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Remarks For The Banquet In Recognition of Fazle Hussain…, 5/2/01 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - What Should We Keep: What Should We Throw Away, 5/16/01 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Thinking About Radios, Books, and Machines, 5/22/01 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - The Wild Card: Creativity and Unpredictability, 5/26/01 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Reflections on Science, Religion, and the Search For Reality, 5/27/01 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Thinking About Radios, Books, and Machines, 6/6/01 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Where Science And Information Management Meet:, 6/12/01 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - The Subtle Texture of Cooperation, 6/19/01 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Reflections on Reporting Reality and Creating Reality, 7/21/01 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - About Teaching Reality and Creating Reality, 8/3/01 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - What Did People Say About Books in 1501, 9/12/01 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - The New Information Media and The Recreation of Reality, 9/20/01 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Books, Computers, and Information: The Recreation of Reality, 9/20/01 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Dyslexia and the Computer, 9/29/01 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - The Language End Game, 10/4/01 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Frankenstein, Faust, and Pygmalion, 10/12/01 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Jane Marcet and Early 19th Century Technical Education, 10/13/01 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - The Trotula: The Story of a Medieval Doctor, 10/23/01 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Inventing Modern:, 10/25/01 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - The Trotula: The Story of a Medieval Doctor, 10/27/01 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - The Trotula: The Story of a Medieval Doctor, 10/27/01 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - The Wounded Story Teller, 11/6/01 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Why The Reckless Survive, 11/15/01 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Inventing Modern: A World Now Left Behind, 11/19/01 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Tension: How We Built Nineteenth Century America, 11/27/01 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Time and Clocks, 12/4/01 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Inventing Modern: A World Now Left Behind, 12/13/01 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Tension: How We Built Nineteeth Century America, 1/17/02 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - On Making Life Livable: The Democratization of Comfort, 1/22/02 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Thoughts on Systems and Energy, 2/6/02 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Invention. A Dangerous Guest, 2/13/02 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - The New Information Media and the Recreation of Reality, 2/28/02 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - The Tensile Century: Iron, Wood, and Structural Buoyancy, 3/7/02 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - A Half Century Later, 3/14/02 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Inventing Modern: A World Now Left Behind, 4/4/02 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - In Memoriam: Catastrophes, Memorials, and Healing, 4/7/02 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - In Memoriam: September 11th & Other Calamities, 4/8/02 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - The Trotula: The Story of a Medieval Doctor, 4/10/02 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - I Lost It At The Movies, 4/13/02 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - The Alchemy of Nuclear Energy and Phase Change, 4/16/02 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Confessions of an Aliterate, 4/24/02 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Looking At the Stars - Going to the Stars: How We Made The Jump, 5/6/02 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Highways of the 1930s: America in Transition, 5/14/02 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Who Am I?, 5/19/02 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Reflections on Building with Stone, 5/23/02 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Reality Forward: Reality Backward: Looking for Reality, 5/25/02 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Engineering education and Shifting Reality, 6/19/02 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - T.V. Script for chang-lin tien's The Retirement Celebration, 6/22/02 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - A Half Century Later, 8/10/02 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - The Back Door Into the Sky, 9/4/02 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Looking at the Stars - Going to the Stars, How We Made the Jump, 9/5/02 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Discussion Points, 9/12/02 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Shifting Sand: Oases of Machines and Ideas, 9/19/02 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Mastered By Nature, We Overcome by Art, 9/24/02 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Ruminations Upon Exponential Invention, 10/8/02 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Frankenstein, Faust, Pygmalion, and Invention, 10/23/02 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Thermodynamics and Theology, 10/27/02 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - I Dressed the Wound and God Healed Him, 11/4/02 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Where Does Engines Come From, 11/7/02 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Freedom Foundation Award Remarks, 11/9/02 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - The Language End Game, 11/9/02 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - The New Information Media and the Recreation of Reality, 11/13/02 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Some Reflections on Ancient Surgery, 11/18/02 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Frankenstein, Faust, and Pygmalion, 11/20/02 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Looking at the Stars- Going to the Stars: How We Made the Jump, 12/4/02 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Thermodynamics and Theology, 12/8/02 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Where Does Engines Come From, 12/10/02 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - The Material Dilemma - At Christmas Time, 12/15/02 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Looking at the Stars- Going to the Stars: How We Made the Jump, 1/16/03 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - More Than a Long Walk, 1/21/03 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Inventing Uneurope: Strangers in a Strange Land, 1/23/03 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Read to Fifth Grade Girls at Ducheshe School, 1/27/03 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Chemistry, Chirality, and Corporate Research, 2/6/03 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - On Paying Attention to the Young, 2/20/03 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Invention, A Dangerous Guest, 2/27/03 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Light, 3/2/03 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Twain, War and Peace, and the Search for a Christian Response, 3/9/03 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Technology, Learning, and Shifting Reality, 3/10/03 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - On Seeing Out the Corner of an Eye, 3/13/03 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - On Paying Attention to the Young, 3/20/03 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - The Library as Communal Expression: A Unique American Idea, 3/28/03 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Nineteenth-Century Medicine and the Calculus of Hope, 4/10/03 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Creativity and the Daemon Within, 4/15/03 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - The Reaction of Reality, 4/25/03 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Looking for History Beneath the Surface, 4/28/03 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - The Polytechnic Tradition and Mechanical Engineering Education, 5/8/03 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Remaking Reality at the News of Science and Information Management, 5/10/03 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Women, Freedom, and the New Technology of Flight, 5/15/03 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Frankenstein, Faust, and Pygmalion, 5/18/03 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Looking for History Beneath the Surface, 5/24/03 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - The Savage Boy Inventor: Find the Road Farm to Modern, 6/24/03 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Foundation for Contemporary Theology Speech, 9/10/03 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Electric Words, Electric Thoughts, Electric Sparks of Change, 9/17/03 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Eye of the Forehead - Eye of the Mind, 10/21/03 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - The Library as Communal Expression, 10/23/03 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Blackboard Notes for Discussion, 10/30/03 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - The Savage Boy Inventor, 10/30/03 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - The Prehistory of Boiling Heat Transfer, 10/31/03 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - The Savage Boy Inventor, 11/6/03 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - The Savage Boy Inventor, 11/13/03 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Savage Boy Inventor, 11/15/03 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - The Back Door Into the Sky, 12/7/03 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Copy of John Lienhard's Article, 12/14/03 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - On Being young and Smart- At the Same Time, 1/5/04 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - On Seeing Out the Corner of an Eye, 1/14/04 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Frankenstein, Faust, and Pygmalion, 1/22/04 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Forest Club Book Club Evening, 1/28/04 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Seeing Earth from the Sky, 1/29/04 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Eye of the Forehead - Eye of the Mind, 2/6/04 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - The Polytechnique /Land - Grant Legacy Napolean to Corvalis, 2/27/04 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Eye of the Forehead - Eye of the Mind, 3/11/04 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - I Show You a Mystery... We Shall Be Changed, 3/16/04 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - The Savage Boy Inventor, 3/18/04 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Things are Seldom What they Seem, 3/25/04 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Thank You From Pershing Middle School, 4/2/04 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Remarks for the ACA Special Achievements Award, 4/3/04 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - The Subtle texture of Cooperation, 4/27/04 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Finding Our Voice - After 60 Years of Searching, 5/1/04 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Another Technology Breakthrough in Education, 5/4/04 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Social Studies Leadership Groups Letters, 5/7/04 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Script for Flights of Fancy, 5/24/04 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Popular Mechanics, 5/27/04 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Rates of Technological Improvement, 6/16/04 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - The Savage Boy Inventor, 7/11/04 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Eyes of the Forehead - Eyes of the Mind, 7/12/04 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Early Flight - Mood, Attitude, and Evolution, 9/11/04 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - The Subtle Texture of Cooperation, 9/16/04 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Notes for a Discussion of Inventing Modern, 9/18/04 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - The Emergence of Women in Math and Science, 10/7/04 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - An Unsettling Glimpse of Invention, 10/20/04 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - It's Only a Theory, 10/21/04 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - From Polytechnique to Populism, 10/21/04 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - The Savage Boy Inventor, 10/25/04 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - The Savage Boy Inventor, 11/4/04 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Tension: How we built 19th Century America, 11/18/04 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - An Unsettling Glimpse of Invention, 12/3/04 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - The Subtle Texture of Cooperation, 12/8/04 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - The Savage Boy Inventor, 12/14/04 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - An Unsettling Glimpse of Invention, 2/4/05 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Comments for the Three Organists Concert, 2/12/05 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - An Unsettling Glimpse of Invention, 2/23/05 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Steam Power before James Watt, 3/10/05 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Frankenstein, Faust and Pygmalion, 3/24/05 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Eye of the Forehead, Eye of the Mind, 4/5/05 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - An Unsettling Glimpse of Invention, 4/28/05 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - So What Was Really Going On?, 5/6/05 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Steam Power Before James Watt, 5/28/05 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Inventing Steam: From Pneuma and Ruach to Turbines, 6/21/05 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - An Unsettling Glimpse of Invention, 6/24/05 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - The Essential Tension in Healing: The Whole Body - Surgical Precision, 8/25/05 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Bread Upon the Waters: Technology and Generosity, 9/13/05 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Fast Presses and the Reinvention of Children, 9/19/05 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Energy Shortages: Learning form Recurrent Crisis, 9/29/05 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Fast Presses and Evolving American Education, 10/7/05 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - About an Honors Degree in Engineering, 10/15/05 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Steam and Speed Come to Boats and Ships, 10/20/05 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Frankenstein, Faust and Pygmalion, 10/23/05 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Book and Author Dinner, 10/28/05 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - An Unsettling Glimpse of Invention, 11/4/05 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - The Arc of Invention, 11/16/05 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Ghosts in the Books, 11/19/05 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - The Savage Boy Inventor, 12/14/05 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - The Savage Boy Inventor, 1/9/06 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Fast Presses and Evolving American Education, 1/19/06 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - The Subtle Texture of Cooperation, 1/31/06 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - An Unsettling Glimpse of Invention, 2/8/06 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Steam Power Before James Watt, 2/21/06 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Steam Power Before James Watt, 2/23/06 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Of Horseshoes, Nails and Future Predictions, 2/24/06 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - An Unsettling Glimpse of Invention, 3/6/06 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Energy Shortages, 3/8/06 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - The Subtle Texture of Cooperation, 3/22/06 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - America, Carved from Wood, Perfumed by Wood, 4/10/06 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Ghosts in the Books, 4/18/06 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Celebrating Archeology, 4/23/06 (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Reflections on Creativity, 4/26/06 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Looking for the Ever-Elusive Elixir of Invention, 4/26/06 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - The Arc of Invention, 5/1/06 (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Looking for a Definition of Hope, 5/4/06 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Steam Power Before James Watt, 5/20/06 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Book Signing Talk, 6/28/06 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Expulsion From Eden (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - Homogenous Nucleation and the Superheated Liquid State (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Hydrodynamic Mechanisms of Pool and External - Flow Boiling Burnout (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Response To Bushaw's Lecture on Math and Reality (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Road Out of Eden, The - Part 1: Adam Leaves Eden (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Road Out of Eden, The - Part 8: The Anthropic Cosmological Principle (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Statistical Mechanics Applied to Non-Microscopic Systems (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Thermodynamic Analogy For the Rainfall Run-Off Problem, A (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Women, Mathematics, and the Creative Process (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Publishing Teaching and Extending - The Balance of Pressures (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Cooking Inside the Inventive Mind (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - About Technological Change (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Panel Remarks for the Ohio Valley (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - A Dialogue on Faculty Functions (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Ever Present Dangers (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - What Are We Here For? (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Clippings, Programs, etc. (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 92)
- Textbooks
  This series consists of various drafts of two textbooks written by Professor Lienhard; Statistical Thermodynamics and A Heat Transfer Textbook. The folders in this series contain preliminary drafts, page proofs, galley proofs, correspondence, and royalty statements for the works.
  - Statistical Thermodynamics
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Introduction, 8/8/97 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Chapters 1,2 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Chapters 3, 4, 5, 6 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Chapters 7, 8 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Chapters 9, 10, 11 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Chapter 12, Appendix A, B, C, D, E (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Index (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Corrected Figure Proofs (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Corrections (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Contents (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Preface (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Introduction, Chapter 1 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Chapter II (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Chapter III (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Chapter IV (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Chapter V (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Chapter VI (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Chapter VII (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Chapter VIII (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Chapter IX (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Chapter X (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Chapter XI (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Chapter XII (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: Appendix (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Final Draft of Copies to Reviewers: List of Tables (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous: Royalty Statement - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 4/25/81 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous: Copyright - Holt, Rinhart Winston, 2/2/97 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous: Correspondence, 1976 - 1986 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous: Errata, 8/12/84 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous: Bookreviews, Summer 1979 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous: Correspondence Hemisphere Publishing Corporation, 1975-1984 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous: Author's Questionnaire Advertising/Promotion Information, 5/69-5/70 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous: Galley Proofs (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Final Draft: Contents (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Final Draft: Chapter I (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Final Draft: Chapter II (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Final Draft: Chapter III (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Final Draft: Chapter IV (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Final Draft: Chapter V (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Final Draft: Chapter VI (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Final Draft: Chapter VII (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Final Draft: Chapter VIII (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Final Draft: Chapter IX (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Final Draft: Chapter X (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Final Draft: Chapter XI (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Final Draft: Chapter XII (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Final Draft: Appendix (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Final Draft: Errata (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous: Solution Manual, 8/77 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Miscellaneous: Correspondence, 1962-1977 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous: Memorandum of Agreement (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous: Corrections to Text, 11/69 - 3/70 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous: Corrections to Text, 7/68 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous: Corrections to Text, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous: Book Reviews, 2/72 - 4/72 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous: Royalty Statements, 1975-1978 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Chapter I, II, III (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Imperfect Gases (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Prediction of Thermodynamic Properties of Simple Liquids (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Non-Physical Approaches to Classical Thermodynamics (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics ME 537,Washington State University, Spring 1964 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics ME 537 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Chapter X (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Chapter XI (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Chapter XI (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Statistical Thermodynamics: Chapter XII (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Preliminary Draft: Chapter I, Spring 1968 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Preliminary Draft: Chapter II, Spring 1968 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Preliminary Draft: Chapter III, Spring 1968 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Preliminary Draft: Chapter IV, Spring 1968 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Preliminary Draft: Chapter V, Spring 1968 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Preliminary Draft: Chapter VI, Spring 1968 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Preliminary Draft: Chapter VII, Spring 1968 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Preliminary Draft: Appendix A, Appendix B, Spring 1968 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Very First Draft: Introduction (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Very First Draft: Chapter I (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Very First Draft: Chapter II (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Very First Draft: Chapter III (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Very First Draft: Notes (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Spring 1966 Draft: Contents, Chapter I,II,III,IV, Appendix A,C (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Spring 1966 Draft: Contents, Chapter I,II,III,IV, Appendix A,C (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Fall 1967 Draft: Chapter I,II,V,VI,XI, Appendix B (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Fall 1967 Draft: Errata, Chapter I,II,IV,V,VI,VII,XI, Appendix A (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Spring 1968 Final Draft: Chapters I,II,III (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Spring 1968 Final Draft: Chapters IV,V,VI (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous: Errata (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous: "not needed pages" (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous: Royalty Statement (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - A Heat Transfer Textbook
    - Early Draft: Chapter 1 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Early Draft: Chapter 2 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Early Draft: Chapter 3 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Early Draft: Chapter 4 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Early Draft: Chapter 5 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Early Draft: Chapter 6 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Early Draft: Chapter 7 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Early Draft: Chapter 8 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Early Draft: Chapter 9 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Early Draft: Chapter 10 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Early Draft: Chapter 11 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Early Draft: Chapter 12 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Class Notes: University of Kentucky ME325 Heat Transfer Problems, Quizzes, & Exams, Spring 1978 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Class Notes: University of Kentucky ME325 Heat Transfer Course Outline & Class Notes, Spring 1978 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Draft: Chapter I, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 15)